# Massimo Guida (He/Him/His), D.M.A. - Composer, Theorist, Educator, Copyist, and Full-Stack Developer

703-100 Hayden Street, Toronto, ON M4Y 3C7 Phone: (647) 808-4073

E-mail: massimo.guidamusic@gmail.com Website: www.massimoguida.com

Soundcloud: https://soundcloud.com/massimo-guida LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/massimo-guida-23b13a30/

GitHub: https://github.com/MG-cpu90

Portfolio: https://mg-cpu90.github.io/assignment8/Develop/index.html

### Profile

Hardworking, serious, polite, and high-achieving Italian-Canadian composer and full-stack developer. Knows multiple languages, and is open-minded and committed to diversity, having lived and attended schools in five countries. Works well both individually and as part of a team. Has extensive research and teaching experience. Seeking employment in web-development or music.

#### Education

UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO, SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES – Toronto, ON Certificate of Completion, Coding Boot Camp, Full–Stack Development – (2020) (Exp	GPA: 4.0/4.0 <b>ected)</b>
UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO, SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES – Toronto, ON Practical Language Certificate, French – (2019–2021) (Expected)	GPA: 4.0/4.0
UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO – Toronto, ON Doctor of Musical Arts, Composition – (2014–2019)	GPA: 4.0/4.0
UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO, SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES – Toronto, ON Conversational Language Certificate, French – (2018–2019)	GPA: 4.0/4.0
UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO – Toronto, ON M.Mus., in Music Composition – (2012–2014)	GPA: 4.0/4.0
UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO – Toronto, ON (High Distinction)  B.Mus. (Hons.), Major in Music Composition, Minor in Spanish – (2008–2012)	GPA: 3.98/4.0
ASSOCIATE BOARD OF THE ROYAL SCHOOLS OF MUSIC – London, UK Grade 8 Advanced Musical Theory and Literacy – (2008)	GPA: PASS
GCE ADVANCED LEVEL DIPLOMA – Brentwood School, Brentwood, UK. 3 A's at A-levels, and 5 A's at AS-levels – (2006–2008)	GPA: 4.0/4.0
LONDON COLLEGE OF MUSIC EXAMINATIONS – London, UK Grade 8 Advanced Guitar, First Class Honours; Graduated with Merit – (2007)	GPA: 3.8/4.0

### Skills Summary

- Perfect pitch & high musical ability; proficient guitarist, composer, copyist, & music theorist; hard-working.
- Problem solving skills, analytical skills, customer service, time management, & administrative tasks.
- Musical, compositional, creative, & artistic skills.
- Interpersonal skills; polite, compassionate & empathetic.
- Research skills; grant & scholarship proposal writing.
- Fluent in English, French, Italian, & Spanish; conversational in Portuguese.

- High level of written & oral correspondence.
- Computer savvy: Microsoft Office, Sibelius, Logic, & Social Media; full-stack developer (Skills: HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node, Git, Ajax, JSON, API, ES6+, SQL).
- Extensive teaching experience.
- Enterprising, diligent, & collaborative.
- Organised & detail oriented; perfectionist.
- Open-minded & committed to diversity.

### Work experience

# FREELANCE MUSIC COPYIST - Toronto, ON, 2014-

 Transcribing, proofreading, and editing musical scores, examples, and analytical graphs to be included in published academic works or library catalogues.

# FREELANCE COMPOSER & ARRANGER - Toronto, ON, 2008-

Transcribing, composing, and arranging music for media and various ensembles for events.

### VESUVIUS ENSEMBLE - VOLUNTEER - Toronto, ON, 2018-

• Assisting with ticket and CD sales, setting up for concerts, and aiding attendees.

### FREELANCE GUITAR & MUSIC THEORY TEACHER - Toronto, ON, 2009-

Taught all levels of guitar and music theory to various different students.

## MUSICAL DIRECTOR, ANIMA MUSIC INC. - Toronto, ON, 2018-2020 - https://www.anima-ai.com/

Created musical rules for the development of AI composition software; produced presentations on research findings.

## TEACHING ASSISTANT, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO - Toronto, ON, 2014-2019

 Planning lessons, teaching tutorials, grading assignments, testing and assisting students, supervising exams, and meeting with professors.

#### RESEARCH ASSISTANT, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO - Toronto, ON, 2014-2019

Assisting professors with their research by transcribing, proofreading, and editing musical examples and analytical
graphs to be included in published works.

#### SUMMER INTERN: ROBETER PRODUCTIONS - North York - Toronto, ON, 2012

 Composed license free underscoring music, aided the production team by recording guitar parts and provided administrative support.

## TEACHER: SMART ABACUS SUMMER SCHOOL & CAMP - Markham, ON, 2011-2012

 Tutored students of various ages in Maths, English, French, and Music. Assigned students homework, tests and prepared syllabi and lessons. Supervised students during field trips.

### GUITAR TEACHER: COSMO SCHOOL OF MUSICS - Richmond Hill, ON, 2009-2010

• Taught different styles of guitar to students of various abilities and ages.

## Awards, Activities & Significant Achievements

- Accepted to the "Orford Music Academy," 2020
- Accepted to "Scarborough Philharmonic's New Generation Composer's Workshop," 2020
- Participated in the "University of Toronto Graduate Music Conference," 2020
- Recipient of the Ontario Graduate Scholarship, 2016–17; 2017–18
- Winner of the Mississauga Festival Choir Competition, 2015
- Winner of the Violet Archer Composition Award, 2015
- Recipient of the *University of Toronto Fellowship*, 2014–15
- Recipient of the Joseph-Armand Bombardier CGS Program: SSHRC Master's Scholarship, 2013–14
- Composed the music for the "Boundless Impact" Promotional Video, the Inaugural Video of the University's new President, and the Faculty of Music "Newsroom" for the University of Toronto, 2013
- Composed "The Fanfare of Illumination" for the University College "Alumni of Influence Gala," 2012
- Recipient of the Lothar Klein Fellowship, University of Toronto, 2012
- Recipient of the Music Alumni Graduating Award, University of Toronto, 2012
- Recipient of the Smart Abacus Teaching Award, 2011 & 2012
- Screen Composer's Guild of Canada Mentorship Bursary Program Finalist, 2011
- Ben McPeek Scholarship & Arthur Plettner Scholarship, University of Toronto, 2011
- Faculty Artist's Scholarship & Gwendolyn Grant Scholarship, University of Toronto, 2010
- Chorister for the Brentwood Cathedral Choir, Brentwood, UK, 2006–2008
- United Kingdom Mathematics Trust Advanced Maths Challenge Silver Medal, 2008

### Biography

Toronto-based Italian-Canadian composer, theorist, copyist, educator, and full–stack developer **Massimo Guida** was born in Modena, Italy, in 1990, and has lived in Canada since 2008. He completed his doctoral studies in composition at the University of Toronto in 2019, under the supervision of Professor Christos Hatzis. He previously also completed his undergraduate and Master's studies in composition at the same institution, during which he studied composition with Professors Norbert Palej, Alexander Rapoport, Chan Ka Nin, and Gary Kulesha, and classical guitar under Eli Kassner. Described as a composer who writes with "a particularly strong melodic inspiration" by *La Scena Musicale* in 2012, in 2015, his song cycle *Confessions* (2014) was the recipient of the *Violet Archer Prize*, while his choral work *Infant Joy* (2013) won the *Mississauga Festival Choir Competition*. Outside of composition, Massimo is deeply interested in music theory and web development, and is currently learning full-stack development. He has also been the recipient of several academic awards, including a SSHRC CGS Master's Scholarship for his Master's research on the music of Alfredo Casella, and multiple Ontario Graduate Scholarships for his doctoral research on tonal structure in Giacomo Puccini's *Turandot* (1926), which was supervised by Professor Steven Vande Moortele. Learn more at: www.massimoguida.com

#### **Published Compositions**

Guida, Massimo, and Augustine. 2015. Confessions: A Song Cycle for Voice and Piano: Based on The Confessions of St. Augustine: 2014.

#### **Conference Presentations**

Guida, Massimo. 2020. "Drama and Tonal Procedure in Giacomo Puccini's 'Turandot' (1926)." Paper presented at the Graduate Music Conference, at the Faculty of Music, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, March 7, 2020.

#### **Performed Compositions**

Rondo-Allegro, for Piano Trio (2018) (Performed March 2019)

*Invenzione per Pianoforte*, for Solo Piano (2016) (Performed March 2019)

A Shropshire Lad (Based on five poems from A.E. Housman's collection of poems of the same name), A Song Cycle for Soprano & Piano (2016) (Performed March 2016)

Three Compositional Studies in Gesture, for Two Violins (2015) (Performed March 2019)

Sonatina per Quintetto da Camera, for Flute, Clarinet, Marimba, Violin, & Cello (2015) (Performed December 2015)

Memory Worked by Mirrors, for Clarinet, Soprano, Percussion, Guitar, & Cello (2014) (Performed May 2014)

Confessions (Based on The Confessions of St. Augustine), A Song Cycle for Soprano & Piano (2014) (Performed April 2014)

Infant Joy, for SATB Choir (2013) (Performed December 2015)

The Fanfare of Illumination, for Brass Ensemble (Written for the University College "Alumni of Influence" Gala, University of Toronto) (2012) (Performed November 2012)

Suite Ottatonica Neobarocca, for Solo Piano (2012) (Performed March 2013)

Ilusões do Carnaval, Study for Two Marimbas (2012) (Performed November 2012)

Rob Ford: The Opera (Scenes 1 & 2) (Libretto by Michael Albano), An Opera in Six Scenes for Soloists & Chamber Orchestra (2012) (Performed January 2012)

Per AC, A Single-Movement Sonata for Solo Piano (2011) (Performed March 2011)

*Preludio per Chitarra*, for Solo Classical Guitar (2011) (Performed February 2012)

Ricordi di una Notte Tenebrosa, i. Sogni Infranti, for String Quartet (2009) (Performed February 2010)

Early Morning Sunrise Over the Water, for Chamber Ensemble (2009) (Performed November 2009)

Psalm 73:23-26, for Soprano & Chamber Ensemble (2008) (Performed December 2008)

Ave Maria, for Soprano & Organ (2008) (Performed July 2010)

Organ Toccata in C minor, for Organ (2008) (Performed November 2008)

Il Sogno, for Flute, Classical Guitar, & Piano (2008) (Performed October 2008)

So Long!, for Jazz Orchestra, Timpani, & Soloists (2008) (Performed June 2008)

Uno Sguardo al Cielo, for Soprano & Chamber Orchestra (2007) (Performed March 2008)